export default [
    { site: "https://ismailyusufcollege.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Western-Philosophy-MCQS.pdf" },
    {
        id: 1,
        question: "The four main divisions of philosophy are metaphysics, epistemology, axiology, and _____.",
        answers: [
            "bioethics",
            "logic",
            "aesthetics",
            "categorical logic",
        ],
        correct_answer: "logic"
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        question: "The study of reality in the broadest sense, an inquiry into the elemental nature of the universe and the things in it, is known as _____.",
        answers: [
            "metaphysics",
            "epistemology",
            "quantum physics",
            "axiology",
        ],
        correct_answer: "metaphysics"
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        question: "Questions like “What is knowledge?” and “What is truth?” are mainstays in the branch of philosophy known as _____.",
        answers: [
            "logic",
            "metaphysics",
            "epistemology",
            "aesthetics",
        ],
        correct_answer: "epistemology"
    },
    {
        id: 4,
        question: "For Socrates, an unexamined life is a tragedy because it results in grievous harm to _____.",
        answers: [
            "the state",
            "the justice system",
            "the body",
            "the soul",
        ],
        correct_answer: "the soul"
    },
    {
        id: 5,
        question: "For Socrates, the soul is harmed by lack of _____.",
        answers: [
            "knowledge",
            "wealth",
            "community",
            "courage",
        ],
        correct_answer: "knowledge"
    },
    {
        id: 6,
        question: "A question-and-answer dialogue in which propositions are methodically scrutinized to uncover the truth is known as _____.",
        answers: [
            "an argument",
            "the Socratic method",
            "the Socratic jest",
            "a debate",
        ],
        correct_answer: "the Socratic method"
    },
    {
        id: 7,
        question: "According to Socrates, a clear sign that a person has _____ is her exclusive pursuit of social status, wealth, power, and pleasure.",
        answers: [
            "philosophical ambition",
            "worldly wisdom",
            "exceptional desires",
            "an unhealthy soul",
        ],
        correct_answer: "an unhealthy soul"
    },
    {
        id: 8,
        question: "The famous statement “An unexamined life is not worth living” is attributed to _____.",
        answers: [
            "Aristotle",
            "John Locke",
            "Socrates",
            "Plato",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Socrates"
    },
    {
        id: 10,
        question: "——— is a Skeptic.",
        answers: [
            "David Hume",
            "Emmanuel Kant",
            "Hegel",
            "None of these",
        ],
        correct_answer: "David Hume"
    },
    {
        id: 11,
        question: "Esseest Percipi is the concept of:",
        answers: [
            "Rene Descartes",
            "Benedict Spinoza",
            "George Berkeley",
            "Francis Bacon",
        ],
        correct_answer: "George Berkeley"
    },
    {
        id: 12,
        question: "The metaphysical view that there are many realities is known as",
        answers: [
            "Dualism",
            "Pluralism",
            "Monism",
            "Non-dualism",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Pluralism"
    },
    {
        id: 13,
        question: "The theory that holds reason as the source of knowledge is",
        answers: [
            "Idealism",
            "Rationalism",
            "Empiricism",
            "None of the above",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Rationalism"
    },
    {
        id: 14,
        question: "Inborn ideas are known as:",
        answers: [
            "Adventitious ideas",
            "Factitious ideas",
            "Innate ideas",
            "a, b & c",

        ],
        correct_answer: "Innate ideas"
    },
    {
        id: 15,
        question: "The Philosophy of Hegel is known as",
        answers: [
            "Phenomenal idealism",
            "Personal idealism",
            "Objective idealism",
            "Absolute idealism",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Absolute idealism"
    },
    {
        id: 16,
        question: "The founder of Positivism is",
        answers: [
            "Saint Simon",
            "C. S Pierce",
            "August Comte",
            "Francis Bacon",
        ],
        correct_answer: "August Comte"
    },
    {
        id: 17,
        question: "The author of Novum Organum is",
        answers: [
            "Rene Descartes",
            "Lemnitzer",
            "John Dewey",
            "Francis Bacon",
        ],
        correct_answer: "John Dewey"
    },
    {
        id: 18,
        question: "The science of values is known as",
        answers: [
            "Axiology",
            "Sociology",
            "Ontology",
            "Cosmology",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Axiology"
    },
    {
        id: 19,
        question: "Metaphysics is the work of",
        answers: [
            "Socrates",
            "Plato",
            "Aristotle",
            "Thales",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        id: 21,
        question: "Early Skepticism is also known as",
        answers: [
            "Pyrrhonism",
            "Positivism",
            "Materialism",
            "Idealism",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Pyrrhonism"
    },
    {
        id: 20,
        question: "The Greek word Pragma means",
        answers: [
            "Truth",
            "Act or deed",
            "Utility",
            "Beauty",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Act or deed"
    },
    {
        id: 22,
        question: "The author of Republic",
        answers: [
            "Socrates",
            "Descartes",
            "Plato",
            "Hume",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Plato"
    },
    {
        id: 23,
        question: "The metaphysical view that there is one ultimate reality is called",
        answers: [
            "Dualism",
            "Pluralism",
            "Monism",
            "None of these",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Monism"
    },
    {
        id: 24,
        question: "According to the modern scientists matter is",
        answers: [
            "Light",
            "Energy",
            "Illusion",
            "All of these",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Energy"
    },
    {
        id: 25,
        question: "——— is a Greek atomist",
        answers: [
            "Democritus",
            "Xenophanes",
            "Xenophon",
            "Zeno",

        ],
        correct_answer: "Democritus"
    },
    {
        id: 26,
        question: "epistemology studies",
        answers: [
            "Origin and Nature of knowledge",
            "Validity of knowledge",
            "Extendofknowledge",
            "a, b & c",
        ],
        correct_answer: "a, b & c"
    },
    {
        id: 27,
        question: "The two branches of Metaphysics are",
        answers: [
            "Religion and Theology",
            "Rationalism and Empiricism",
            "Ontology and Cosmology",
            "Materialism and Spiritualism",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Ontology and Cosmology"
    },
    {
        id: 28,
        question: "The three distempers of learning according to. Francis Bacon are:",
        answers: [
            "Mind, body and God",
            "Ideas, experience and thought.",
            "Fantastical, contentious and delicate",
            "Tribe, cave and theatre",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Fantastical, contentious and delicate"
    },
    {
        id: 29,
        question: "Philosophy is concerned with",
        answers: [
            "The irrational",
            "Beauty",
            "The ideal",
            "Experimentation",
        ],
        correct_answer: "The ideal"
    },
    {
        id: 30,
        question: "Ethics is a ———",
        answers: [
            "Positive science",
            "Normative science",
            "Descriptive science",
            "None of these",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Normative science"
    },
    {
        id: 31,
        question: "——— seeks to clarify and refine the process of knowing",
        answers: [
            "Epistemology",
            "Axiology",
            "Metaphysics",
            "Ethics",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Epistemology"
    },
    {
        id: 32,
        question: "The Latin word ——— is the root of rationalism",
        answers: [
            "Sophia",
            "Reason",
            "Ratio",
            "Experiential",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Ratio"
    },
    {
        id: 33,
        question: "———— insists on a a priori knowledge.",
        answers: [
            "Positivism",
            "Empiricism",
            "Rationalism",
            "None of these",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Rationalism"
    },
    {
        id: 34,
        question: "Berkeley argues that all knowledge is derived from",
        answers: [
            "Impression",
            "Ideas",
            "Axioms",
            "Postulates",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Ideas"
    },
    {
        id: 35,
        question: "———— helps in getting correct knowledge through anumana",
        answers: [
            "Vyapti",
            "Paksha",
            "Sadhya",
            "Badha",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Vyapti"
    },
    {
        id: 36,
        question: "The words of a trustworthy person is known as",
        answers: [
            "Satya",
            "Dharma",
            "Aptavakya",
            "Linga",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Aptavakya"
    },
    {
        id: 37,
        question: "A theory is a conclusion, where as a method is a",
        answers: [
            "Style",
            "Manner",
            "Inference",
            "Procedure",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Procedure"
    },
    {
        id: 38,
        question: "Philosophy is the root and science is the",
        answers: [
            "Fruit",
            "Branch",
            "Nourishment",
            "Stem",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Fruit"
    },

    {
        id: 39,
        question: "Who said ? Philosophy is the Science of sciences",
        answers: [
            "Plato",
            "Voltaire",
            "August's Comte",
            "Russell",
        ],
        correct_answer: "August's Comte"
    },
    {
        id: 40,
        question: "———— said “whatever is. Clearly and distinctly perceived is true”",
        answers: [
            "Locke",
            "Berkeley",
            "Descartes",
            "None of these",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Descartes"
    },
    {
        id: 41,
        question: "According to Skepticism knowledge is ———",
        answers: [
            "Certain",
            "Possible",
            "Uncertain",
            "None of these",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Uncertain"
    },
    {
        id: 42,
        question: "The two Heterodox schools in Indian Philosophy are:",
        answers: [
            'Nyaya and Vaisesika',
            'Buddhism and Jainism',
            'Sankhya and Yoga',
            'Purva and Uttaramimamsa',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Buddhism and Jainism"
    },
    {
        id: 43,
        question: "The father of philosophy:",
        answers: [
            'Descartes',
            'Thales',
            'Aristotle',
            'Francis Bacon',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Thales"
    },
    {
        id: 44,
        question: "A Treatise of Human Nature is the work of:",
        answers: [
            'Karl Popper',
            'John Dewey',
            'Bertrand Russell',
            'David Hume',
        ],
        correct_answer: "John Dewey"
    },
    {
        id: 45,
        question: "The most original contribution of Americans thought at the end of nineteenth century:",
        answers: [
            'Pragmatism',
            'Positivism',
            'Empiricism',
            'Rationalism',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Pragmatism"
    },
    {
        id: 46,
        question: "Who is a philosopher, in the original sense of the word?",
        answers: [
            'A person primarily interested in the truth about moral matters.',
            'Someone who studies the stars and planets.',
            'A clever and tricky argues.',
            'A lover and pursuer of wisdom, regardless of the subject matter.',
        ],
        correct_answer: "A lover and pursuer of wisdom, regardless of the subject matter."
    },
    {
        id: 47,
        question: "The three main divisions of Philosophy are metaphysics, epistemology, and ———",
        answers: [
            'Axiology',
            'Sociology',
            'Anthropology',
            'Cosmology',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Axiology"
    },
    {
        id: 48,
        question: "Descartes was a ———thinker",
        answers: [
            'Emperical',
            'Rational',
            'Materialistic',
            'Idealistic',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Rational"
    },
    {
        id: 49,
        question: "Which American mathematician philosopher laid the foundation of Pragmatism",
        answers: [
            'William James',
            'J. Dewey',
            'C.S Pierce',
            'Spinoza',
        ],
        correct_answer: "C.S Pierce"
    },
    {
        id: 50,
        question: "The Problem of Knowledge was written by ———",
        answers: [
            'Aristotle',
            'Plato',
            'A.J Ayer',
            'Collingwood',
        ],
        correct_answer: "A.J Ayer"
    },
    {
        id: 51,
        question: "Spinoza's method is known as———",
        answers: [
            'Axiomatic',
            'Theoretical',
            'Geometrical',
            'Doubt',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Axiomatic"
    },
    {
        id: 52,
        question: "Who said? “God is dead”",
        answers: [
            'Schopenhauer',
            'Popper',
            'Sartre',
            'Nietzsche',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Nietzsche"
    },
    {
        id: 53,
        question: "Who is the father of existentialism?",
        answers: [
            'Soren Kierkegaard',
            'Camus',
            'Sartre',
            'Heidegger',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Soren Kierkegaard"
    },
    {
        id: 54,
        question: "——— Introduced the term Aesthetics",
        answers: [
            'Kant',
            'Hegel',
            'Baumgarten',
            'Aristotle',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        id: 55,
        question: "Socratic method is",
        answers: [
            'Skeptical',
            'Conceptual',
            'Conversational',
            'All of these',
        ],
        correct_answer: "All of these"
    },
    {
        id: 56,
        question: "The Skepticism of Descartes is known as ———",
        answers: [
            'Pure Skepticism',
            'Phenomenal Skepticism',
            'Methodological Skepticism',
            'None of these',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Methodological Skepticism"
    },
    {
        id: 57,
        question: "Who said 'Accept nothing as true which we do not perceive clearly and distinctly'",
        answers: [
            'Descartes',
            'Spinoza',
            'Leibniz ',
            'Kant',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Descartes"
    },
    {
        id: 58,
        question: "——— explained the world with the theory of Monads",
        answers: [
            'Democritus',
            'St. Anselm',
            'Leibniz',
            'William James',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Leibniz"
    },
    {
        id: 59,
        question: "——— is said to be the origin of Philosophy",
        answers: [
            'Greed',
            'Wonder',
            'Fear',
            'None of these',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Wonder"
    },
    {
        id: 60,
        question: "The mind body relationship theory of Descartes is known as———",
        answers: [
            'Psycho physical parallelism',
            'Interactionism',
            'Pre established harmony',
            'None of these',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Interactionism"
    },
    {
        id: 61,
        question: "Wittgenstein says that language is a",
        answers: [
            'Statement',
            'Picture of reality',
            'Judgement',
            'Concept',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Picture of reality"
    },
    {
        id: 62,
        question: "———— rejected Metaphysics as meaningless",
        answers: [
            'Logical positivists',
            'Rationalists',
            'Idealists',
            'Spiritualists',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Logical positivists"
    },
    {
        id: 63,
        question: "——— is known as queen Science",
        answers: [
            'Mathematics',
            'Physics',
            'Philosophy',
            'Psychology',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Philosophy"
    },
    {
        id: 64,
        question: "Dialectical materialism is the theory of———",
        answers: [
            'Hegel',
            'Marx',
            'Nietzsche',
            'Schopenhauer',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Marx"
    },
    {
        id: 65,
        question: "——— is the father of Spiritualistic pluralism",
        answers: [
            'Locke',
            'Dewey',
            'Leibniz',
            'W. James',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Leibniz"
    },
    {
        id: 66,
        question: "The author of Passions of the Soul is",
        answers: [
            'Spinoza',
            'A.J Ayer',
            'Aristotle',
            'Plato',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Plato"
    },
    {
        id: 67,
        question: "——— said 'Philosophy is the science of knowledge'.",
        answers: [
            'Schelling',
            'Fitche',
            'Marx',
            'Bruno',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Fitche"
    },
    {
        id: 68,
        question: "Transcendental aesthetic deals with the theory of",
        answers: [
            'Understanding',
            'Sensations',
            'Aesthetic Judgement',
            'Moral Judgement',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Sensations"
    },
    {
        id: 69,
        question: "It is the art of ——— which brings other men's ideas to birth",
        answers: [
            'Deception',
            'Oratory',
            'Intellectual midwifery',
            'All of these',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Intellectual midwifery"
    },
    {
        id: 70,
        question: "The 18th century German thinker who initiated dramatic changes in the field of Aesthetics is ———",
        answers: [
            'Leibniz',
            'Kant',
            'Nietzsche',
            'Schelling',
        ],
        correct_answer: "Kant"
    },
    {
        id: 71,
        question: "William James studied which aspect of religion?",
        answers: [
            "Religious experience",
            "Religious symbolism",
            "Religious myths",
            "Religious rituals",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Religious experience"
    },
    {
        id: 72,
        question: "Which of these best describes the noetic quality?",
        answers: [
            "Love",
            "Time",
            "Knowledge",
            "Emotion",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Knowledge"
    },
    {
        id: 73,
        question: "Which of these is a way to study and write about religion that is considered a religious endeavour?",
        answers: [
            "Theology",
            "Moral philosophy",
            "Religious studies",
            "Biblical criticism",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Theology"
    },
    {
        id: 74,
        question: "Which of these is not one of these seven dimensions of religion?",
        answers: [
            "The practical dimensions",
            "The emotional dimensions",
            "The divine dimensions",
            "The mythic dimensions",
        ],
        correct_answer: "The divine dimensions"
    },
    {
        id: 75,
        question: "Which of these religious traditions teaches the supreme importance of harmony in the family, community and state?",
        answers: [
            "Confucianism",
            "Judaism",
            "Hinduism",
            "Christianity",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Confucianism"
    },
    {
        id: 76,
        question: "Which is not attributed of god?",
        answers: [
            "Omnipotent",
            "Omnicent",
            "Omnipresent",
            "Natural",
        ],
        correct_answer: "Natural"
    }
]
